Hello everyone and welcome to
English Pod, my name is Marco.
My name is Catherine
and today's show is a
continuation of our series about
giving a presentation in English.
So we're talking about a
special line of computers here.
That's right and on this occasion
we're going to compare two companies.
So we're going to try
to tell everyone what the
difference is between our
company and the competitors.
All right, so we learned
a lot of great phrases
and words for making
comparisons in last week's show.
We're going to hear some of these again.
Let's listen to the dialogue.
Now of course with all this cutting
edge technology, there must be a catch.
You might ask yourself,
"I bet the retail price
will be too much for most
consumers," you might say.
Well, you'd be wrong.
Yes, of course the X420 is aimed at the
luxury market, but if you compare the price
of our leading competitors, the X420
represents incredible value for money.
At only 15,000 RMB,
it is far more affordable
and far more attractive than almost
every leading brand and model.
So what differentiates
us from our competitors?
Well, if we compare
oranges, luxury MP40
range, then we can really
highlight some of the differences.
Now, of course, orange
has an enviable record
for producing
revolutionary and top-class
products, and I must admit the
MP40 is a breathtaking machine.
However, for most consumers, the MP40
is simply far too expensive to consider.
Compared with the
X420, it is more expensive
and there's no doubt
that considering the
quality and workmanship
that goes into the X420,
we really win hands-down
on value for money.
Also, if you compare
the after-sales service
we offer, I think we
can proudly boast the
best customer service facilities
in the whole laptop sector.
As opposed to most of
our rivals, we guarantee
quality, we guarantee service
and we guarantee reliability.
The questions we must ask ourselves
are, "What does the alpha brand stand for?
" And also, "How can we set
ourselves apart from our competitors?
" The answer to both of these
questions is the same, my friends.
Alpha stands first and foremost for
quality, for excellence and for service.
If we always stick to this
philosophy, then I'm confident that
we will really be able to expand
our market share significantly.
Okay, let me move on now to give you an
idea of our marketing campaign for the X420.
All right, we're back, so now let's take a
look at these phrases on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
Our first phrase comes from the
very first sentence of today's dialogue.
We heard this phrase
cutting-edge technology.
Now Marco, what does cutting-edge mean?
Okay, so as you see in the dialogue, we're
talking about technology and if technology
is cutting-edge, it
basically means it's new,
it's very modern, it's
the newest you can get.
It's the most advanced perhaps.
That's right.
So, what's an example of a
current cutting-edge technology?
Can you think of something?
So for example, when
we talk about mobile
phones that can now
connect to the internet,
you can send emails,
they have many features,
even two cameras and
touch sensitive screens.
This is a type of cutting-edge technology.
Okay, it's the most new
technology, the newest.
That's right.
So, after that, we heard
another phrase, this
is a bit different, this is
more of a business phrase.
We have this retail price.
I bet the retail price will be too much.
So what is a retail price and how
is it different from a regular price?
Okay, so the retail
price is basically the
amount of money that you
pay for something at the store.
Exactly.
So, if I go to a store
and I buy a computer
for $1,000, I know that
the store, they bought
the computer for less money, otherwise they
don't earn any money, it's a bad business.
That's right.
The retail price is higher than the
actual price, the cost of production.
So, retail price just
basically means exactly
what you said, Marco,
how much you would spend
on something, how much
something costs in a store.
That's right, that's why
they're called retail stores.
Exactly.
Now, moving on, when
we're discussing the X420 this
computer, Mr. Ford says that
it's aimed at the luxury market.
That means that this
company would like to sell
the computer in the luxury market, the
luxury market is not the normal market.
It's the market for very expensive,
very beautiful, very nice things.
Luxury items, luxury brands
are very, very expensive.
That's right.
So, for example, a car
such as a Mercedes Benz
might be aimed at the
luxury market, whereas
a car like a Honda Civic is aimed at
maybe more of a middle-class market.
Exactly.
Or in clothing, you
could say Gucci is a luxury
brand, right, whereas the gap or
something is a regular consumer brand.
That's right.
So, this is what we talk about
when we refer to a luxury market.
Now, moving on to the
description of the X420, Mr.
Ford says that it's amazing quality and
that the workmanship is very, very good.
So, workmanship is
related to the word work.
And now, workmanship
means how something is made.
Generally, when we talk
about luxury goods, we
expect the workmanship
to be very, very high quality.
That means that the way that
these things are made is the best.
That's right.
It's not going to break in one day.
Usually I think when you
talk about workmanship
or luxury items like this, maybe
the part of it is made by hand.
So, this is what we talk
about workmanship is
how skilled that that
person is or how skilled
his hands are to make this
great piece of luxury good.
Exactly.
So, a very good example in the
world of music is the strativarius violin.
So, strativarius violins
are very, very expensive
because the workmanship is the best
quality in the history of world music.
That's right.
Very good.
So, that's what we talk about workmanship.
You can apply it to many different things.
But moving on to our
last word for language
takeaway today, another
nice business phrase that
we talk about specifically
in sales is market share.
Now, Marco, describe to me market
share because I know what a market is.
It's where things are bought
and sold, but what is a share?
Market share.
So, in this case, we're
talking about computers.
So, a market share is how
much a company owns in
the market or how much
they sell in this market.
So, for example, if we
have a city of a thousand
people and everyone
there buys computers,
if we sell computers to 500 people of that
city, that means we own a 50% market share.
Okay.
So, a market share is usually
like a percentage, right?
It's a piece of this big pie.
That's right.
So, everyone is always
fighting for more market share.
However, sales more has big market share.
So, in the world of televisions, would you
say that Sony has a large market share and
in televisions?
Probably, although I think maybe
Samsung has bigger market share or LG.
I don't know.
Let's see.
This is the thing with
market shares is that
there are so many
brands in a certain industry
that everyone has maybe a little piece of
the pie or maybe one has a bigger piece.
I see.
All right.
Well, that's it for language takeaway.
I hope you guys have
learned something there.
We're going to be back in a
moment with fluency builder.
Now of course, with all this cutting
edge technology, there must be a catch.
You might ask yourself,
"I bet the retail price
will be too much for most
consumers," you might say.
Well, you'd be wrong.
Yes, of course the
X420 is aimed at the
luxury market, but if
you compare the price of
our leading competitors, the X420
represents incredible value for money.
Not only 15,000 RMB,
it is far more affordable
and far more attractive than almost
every leading brand and model.
So what differentiates
us from our competitors?
Well, if we compare
oranges, luxury MP40
range, then we can really
highlight some of the differences.
Now, of course, orange
has an enviable record for
producing revolutionary
and top-class products.
And I must admit, the MP40
is a breathtaking machine.
However, for most consumers, the MP40
is simply far too expensive to consider.
Compared with the
X420, it is more expensive
and there's no doubt
that considering the
quality and workmanship
that goes into the X420,
we really win hands
down on value for money.
Also, if you compare the after-sales service
we offer, I think we can proudly boast
the best customer service
facilities in the whole laptop sector.
As opposed to most of
our rivals, we guarantee
quality, we guarantee service
and we guarantee reliability.
The questions we must ask ourselves
are, what does the alpha brand stand for?
And also, how can we set
ourselves apart from our competitors?
The answer to both of these
questions is the same, my friends.
Alpha stands first and foremost for
quality, for excellence and for service.
If we always stick to this
philosophy, then I'm confident that
we will really be able to expand
our market share significantly.
Okay, let me move on now to give you an
idea of our marketing campaign for the X420.
Alright, we're back, so now let's
take a look at Fluency Builder.
Fluency Builder.
So the first phrase I
would like to look at in
Fluency Builder is very
important for consumers.
That means people who buy
things are very interested in this thing.
We call it Value for Money.
That's right.
When Mr. Ford was
talking about the X420, he
said it represents incredible value
for money at only 15,000 RMB.
Okay, so 15,000 RMB sounds
like a lot of money to me.
But he's saying that the value of the
product is very good considering the price.
That's right.
And that's what the
phrase value for money is.
As you said, the quality
and how much you
are getting for this
product compared to how
much you're paying
for it is very, very good.
So the idea is it should be
more expensive, but it's not.
So the value considering
the price is actually very good.
So maybe I could say that this computer,
this Apple computer, it's expensive.
It's $1,500, but the
value for money is great
because I'll have this
computer for five years.
Another computer might break
and I have to buy a new one.
And also you can describe value
for money as something good or bad.
For example, the same computer you can say,
it doesn't represent good value for money.
So maybe you paid more than
what you're actually getting.
There was a bad deal.
It was a bad deal.
That's right.
Great.
Well, the next phrase
is an interesting one.
It's in the sentence where
we talked about workmanship.
So semester four was
describing the X420 and he
said, it really wins hands
down on a value for money.
That's right.
So the phrase that we're going
to take a look at is hands down.
So what does he mean when he says that
workmanship for the X420 wins hands down?
So this is a very spoken English phrase
and it has nothing to do with your hands.
It means, well, I guess
it could hands down.
I'm not really sure what
the literal meaning is.
But when we say it, we mean that
something is without competition.
So there is no doubt in my mind.
This is absolutely the
best in value for money.
And so maybe if I say, oh, well, there are
two or three computers, they're all nice.
Nothing is hands down.
But if I say, listen, this IBM computer
is hands down the best on the market.
That means there's no other competition.
It is the best.
So you can't really argue with that,
it's the best, no arguments there.
No arguments exactly hands down.
He is hands down the best
baseball player I've ever seen.
Okay, very good.
Okay.
So now moving on to
our next phrase, when
Mr. Ford again was talking
about now the company,
he said that the alpha brand
is, what does it stand for?
And he said that it stands
first and foremost for quality.
Okay, so this means
you think about first and
foremost, this means
above everything else.
So alpha means a lot of things.
They make good computers,
they're a strong company.
But first and foremost, it means quality.
It means that more
important than any other thing
that alpha brand does,
quality is the most important.
Okay, so basically
we're seeing the first
thing and the most
important thing is quality.
Quality.
So that's what you mean
when you say first and foremost.
So you can say for
example, when I'm looking
for a car, price is the first and
foremost important quality.
Okay, so we're talking about, you know, for
Marco, the most important factor, the most
important part of
buying a car is the price.
That's right.
So moving on to our
last phrase now, when
Mr. Ford was ending
this part of his speech,
he said that we always stick
to this philosophy to stick to.
So stick is a verb and a noun, if you're
familiar with the noun, it's different from
what we're talking
about today, to stick to,
remember that as a
phrase, to stick to something.
So to stick to means to continue doing it,
okay, you're going to hear this a lot when
you talk about sports
or even in the office,
I could say, listen, Marco,
I don't want you to quit.
I really want you to stick to this project.
Okay, so to continue doing to
not give up, don't give up, right?
So you could say
this to a child also, you
know, I know you want
to quit playing soccer,
but I think you should
stick to it, to stick
to it, that means to
continue playing not to quit.
Okay, very good.
So it's a very nice, and
maybe spoken English
phrase, which means
continue doing to not
give up to be persuasive,
right, to stick to something.
I want to stick to it,
you should stick to this.
Okay, very good.
So a lot of phrases here, I think we've
taken a look at a lot of things here.
Maybe we should go back.
Let's review one last time the
dialogue, and we'll be back in a bit.
Now of course, with all this cutting
edge technology, there must be a catch.
You might ask
yourself, I bet the retail
price will be too much for
most consumers, you might say.
Well, you'd be wrong.
Yes, of course the
X420 is aimed at the
luxury market, but if you compare
the price of our leading competitors.
The X420 represents
incredible value for money.
At only 15,000 RMB,
it is far more affordable
and far more attractive than almost
every leading brand and model.
So what differentiates
us from our competitors?
Well, if we compare
oranges, luxury MP40
range, then we can really
highlight some of the differences.
Now of course, orange
has an enviable record for
producing revolutionary
and top-class products.
But I must admit, the MP40
is a breathtaking machine.
However, for most consumers, the MP40
is simply far too expensive to consider.
Compared with the X420,
it is more expensive and
there's no doubt that
considering the quality
and workmanship that goes into the X420, we
really win hands-down on value for money.
Also, if you compare
the after-sales service
we offer, I think we
can proudly boast the
best customer service facilities
in the whole laptop sector.
As opposed to most of
our rivals, we guarantee
quality, we guarantee service
and we guarantee reliability.
The questions we must ask ourselves
are, what does the alpha brand stand for?
And also, how can we set
ourselves apart from our competitors?
The answer to both of these
questions is the same, my friends.
Alpha stands first and foremost for
quality, for excellence and for service.
If we always stick to this
philosophy, then I'm confident that
we will really be able to expand
our market share significantly.
Okay, let me move on now to give you an
idea of our marketing campaign for the X420.
All right, so that's all the time
we have for today on this series.
Be sure to check out the
next part next week where
we're going to continue
talking about presentations.
And as you can see, it's
very business-oriented,
but you can apply everything that
you learn to other situations as well.
Exactly, these phrases like
hands down and to stick to.
These aren't business
phrases, these are
words you can use in
business, but I use these
in my everyday life and I
think that with a little bit of
practice, you guys can sound
really, really fluent in English.
And these phrases are
a good place to start.
That's right.
So if you have any
questions, any doubts or
comments, you can visit
our website, englishpot.
com, where we'll be there.
See you guys soon.
Bye.
[ Music ]